Buffalo AFL-CIO Council Miscellaneous Documents 5453
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Buffalo AFL-CIO Council Miscellaneous Documents
1937-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Buffalo AFL-CIO Council
5453
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records of the Buffalo AFL-CIO Council.
5623345
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 09, 1996
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Scope and Contents
This collection is arranged in four series: Proceedings, American Labor Party (ALP), Political Action Committees (PAC), and Miscellaneous Documents. Correspondents in Series III-IV include Sidney Hillman, Chairman of CIO-PAC, and Jacob Potofsky, Chair of the Fundraising Committee under CIO-PAC.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arrangement
Series I. Proceedings
Series II. American Labor Party (ALP)
Series III. Political Action Committees (PAC)
Series IV. Miscellaneous Documents
Biographical / Historical
The American Labor Party (ALP) was established in 1936 by labor leaders in the AFL and CIO out of the Labor's Non-Partisan League and Social Democratic Federation. The CIO Political Action Committee (CIO-PAC) was established in July 1943 to support the 1944 re-election of President Franklin D. Roosevelt and to promote CIO-endorsed political candidates at the local and national level. The committee was chaired by Sidney Hillman, head of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA), from 1943 to 1946.
AFL-CIO. Buffalo Council
5623345
- Series I. Proceedings
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Note - Some say "Proceeding of the Executive Board of
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings. Buffalo Federation of Labor, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II. American Labor Party (ALP)
  - American Labor Party Committee Officers Lists, 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Labor Party Correspondence, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    1 photo of American Labor Party office door
  - American Labor Party Committees, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Labor Party: Joint PAC-ALP Planning Committee, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Labor Party: Legislative Action, Primary Elections, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series III. Political Action Committees (PAC)
  - PAC George Addes Correspondence, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Political Action Ward Clubs, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - PAC Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publicity - Local PAC Pamphlet and News Clippings, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Publicity - National PAC, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - PAC Slingers: Election Flyers and Pamphlets, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - PAC: Syracuse "Political Street Guide" and "Erie and Niagara Superway", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - PAC Correspondence, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Statement of Sidney Hillman Before the Special Committee of the House to Investigate Campaign Expenditures (August 28, 1944). Pamphlet titled "The People are On The March" by Henry A. Wallace.
  - PAC Office Records, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - UAW Political Action, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - PAC Workers, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - PAC Council Correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - PAC Council Correspondence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - PAC Correspondence and Voting Records, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - PAC Correspondence and Publications - Pamphlet of the Month, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - PAC Current Material: Correspondence and Election Flyers, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - PAC Newspapers, Memo from PAC, Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - National PAC Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - PAC Correspondence and Election Brochures, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Niagara Frontier PAC: Financial Statements, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - PAC Newspaper Clippings and Voting Records, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous Documents
  - The New Republic: A Congress to Win the War, parts one and two, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Political Periodicals and PAC Correspondence, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1944 Presidential Election Materials (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Facts for November: Men and Issues in the 1946 Congressional Elections, part two (Box 3, Folder 4)
    2 copies of part two
  - Magazines/Newspapers and Raffle Ticket Receipt Books, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PAC Memos and Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - PAC Finances, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Suggestions for PAC District Leaders, Finances, Raffle Records, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Niagara Frontier PAC Registration and Time-off to Vote Cards, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Niagara Frontier PAC Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - PAC Convention Duplicate Credential Forms, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Western New York CIO-PAC, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Various correspondence, receipt book enclosed
  - CIO-PAC 1948 Convention and Resolutions (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - PAC Requests for Endorsement and Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - PAC Correspondence and 1948 Election Promotion (Box 3, Folder 15a)
  - PAC Newsletters and Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 15b)
  - CIO-PAC Finances, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - CIO-PAC: Duplicate and Original Credential Forms, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - PAC Newsletters and Opinion Report, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook Pages: Clippings about 1948 Election Results (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Central Labor Council, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Monthly record by trade, by local attendance or payment?
  - Scrap Book Pages, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Newspaper clippings from "Buffalo Federation of Labor News"
  - Newspapers, Scrapbook Pages, Cornell Extension Bulletin, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - CIO-PAC Election Posters, 1944-1947 (Mapcase folder 4)